Finding Aid for the Herbert Charles Sanborn Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Correspondence - Incoming, Incoming correspondence of 4,326 letters, 235 post cards, and 70 telegrams. Alphabetically arranged, letters are typescript, holograph, and carbon copies. There are several circular and mimeographed. 1 Letters signed with initials only and with 1 name only are found at e
  - Turner, Walter (1), Feb. 13, 1946 (poet card) (Box 15)
  - Tuve, Rosammd (1), Jan. 2, 1953 (post card) (Box 15)
  - Tweet, L. (1), May 12, 1950 (Box 15)
  - Tween Hills Kennel (2), Dec. 19, 1951, (n.d.) (Box 15)
  - Twining, Mrs. E. (1), Hay 11, 1950 (Box 15)
  - Twining, S.J. (3), Nov. 1, 1949, May 7, 1950 (telegram), May 8, 1950 (Box 15)
  - Tyler, John Paul (1), June 13, 1924 (Box 15)
  - Van Brunt, Frances R. (4), Dec.2, 1952, Feb. 24, 1953, Aug. 11, 1954, Oct. 17, 1954 (telegram) (Box 16)
  - Van Hyning, Lyrl Clark (3), May 12, 1958, Apr. 7, 1959 (post card), Feb. 12, 1960 (post card) (Box 16)
  - Van Nagell, S.M. (2), Feb. 1952, (n.d.) (Box 16)
  - Van Susteren, Urban P. (1), Sept.. 1952 (Box 16)
  - Von Glahn, Louise (6), Apr. 9, 1935, May 1, 1935, Sept. 11, 1935, Sept. 30, 1935, Nov. 22, 1935, Nov. 29, 1944 (Box 16)
  - Vandemark, H.M. (5), Dec. 31, 1946, Feb. 11, 1947, Feb. 17, 1947, Mar. 13, 1947, Mar. 28, 1947 (Box 16)
  - Vanderbilt Faculty Club (7), May 2, 1955, (6 with no dates) (Box 16)
  - Vanlandingham, Homer W. (1), July 24, 1944 (Box 16)
  - Vaughan, Earl (1), Oct. 15, 1946 (Box 16)
  - Vaughn, Williams. (1), Nov. 24, 1952 (Box 16)
  - Vennard, W.B. (4), May 13, 1955, Dec. 18, 1955, Dec. 8, 1956, (n.d.) (Box 16)
  - Vetter, S.A. (1), Sept. 30, 1953 (Box 16)
  - Viereck, George Sylvester (4), May 1, 1919, Dec. 23, 1952, Apr. 1954, Jan. 1955 (Box 16)
  - Vigor, Burton A. (6), Feb. 23, 1944, Mar. 15, 1944, June 27, 1944, July 20, 1944, Oct. 12, 1944, Dec. 11, 1944 (Box 16)
  - Village View Turkey Ranch (2), Feb. 22, 1945 (post card), Feb. 28, 1945 (post card) (Box 16)
  - Vlastos, Gregory (1), Apr. 23, 1957 (Box 16)
  - Vogt, Ernest L. (1), Nov. 10, 1947 (Box 16)
  - Volkert, D. Gregory (2), Mar. 22, 1945, Nov. 9, 1945 (Box 16)
  - Vorovka, Karel (2), Dec. 15, 1926, Mar. 23, 1927 (Box 16)
  - Waggoner, Violet (1), Nov. 28, 1958 (Box 16)
  - Wagner, Alice (16), Nov. 30, 1950, Jan. 4, 1951 (post card), Jan. 24, 1951, Apr. 20, 1951, May 21, 1951, June 26, 1951, July 2, 1951, July 24, 1951, July 24, 1951, Sept. 13, 1951, Dec. 17, 1951, Dec. 17, 1952, Mar. 24, 1953, Hay 29, 1953, Jan. 4, 1954, (n.d.) (Box 16)
  - Walder, D.T. (1), Dec. 1, 1953 (Box 16)
  - Waldrop, Eleanor Lanier (1), Oct. 16, 1952 (Box 16)
  - Waldrop, Frank C. (2), Nov. 19, 1952, May 21, 1953 (Box 16)
  - Wall, Tom Jr. (1), Dec. 18, 1952 (Box 16)
  - Wallace, S.R. Jr. (1), Sept. 10, 1943 (to C.P. Heinlein) (Box 16)
  - Walsh, Kate and Ed (1) (Box 16)
  - Walters, J.C. (1), Mar. 11, 1951 (to Mrs. Eugene Sullivan) (Box 16)
  - Walther, Elmer A. (1), Aug. 28, 1943 (Box 16)
  - Walton, Chas. D. (1), Dec. 8, 1943 (Box 16)
  - Walton, J.D. (1), Mar. 13, 1959 (Box 16)
  - Walz, John A. (1), Sept. 22, 1943 (Box 16)
  - Ward, Helen L. (1), July 29, 1958 (Box 16)
  - Ward, J.B. (3), Dec. 27, 1943, May 9, 1944, May 15, 1944 (Box 16)
  - Warden, Margaret Lindsley (1), Apr. 4, 1951 (post card) (Box 16)
  - Ware, leanor (2), July 8, 1948, Mar. 7, 1960 (Box 16)
  - Warner, W.E. Jr. (1), (date illegible) (Box 16)
  - Warren, Howard C. (7), Sept. 10, 1930, Aug. 26, 1931 (to Horace B.English), May 9, 1932, Dec. 24, 1932, Jan. 7, 1933 (post card), Jan. 27, 1933 (post card), May 14, 1933 (Box 16)
  - Warren, Natalie Overall (1), Feb. 15,1963 (Box 16)
  - Warren, Robert Penn (7), May 6, 1944, Hay 7, 1945, May 22, 1945, June 26, 1945, Jan. 5, 1951, Oct. 22, 1952, (n.d.) (Box 16)
  - Warren, William H. (5), Oct. 5, 1927, May 24, 1942, Mar. 11, 1950, ept. 23, 1951, Dec. 24, 1952 (Box 16)
  - Warrick, C.W. (1), Sept. 14, 1957 (Box 16)
  - Washington, Mrs. Francis E. (1), Dec. 31, 1952 (Box 16)
  - Washington, Francis E. (1), Apr. 20, 1955 (Box 16)
  - Waterfield, S. (1), Feb. 15, 1949 (Box 16)
  - Weatherford, W.D. (1), Nov. 7, 1931 (Box 16)
  - Webb, Ruth (4), .f.pr. 26, 1944, May 2, 1944, May 30, 1944, July 16, 1944 (Box 16)
  - Webb, Sam C. (1), May 4, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Webb, W.E. (5), Jan. 29, 1944, Mar. 3, 1944, June 13, 1944, Nov. 29, 1944, July 31, 191+4 (Box 16)
  - Webb, Wilse B. (2), Dec. 4, 1957, Feb. 9, 1959 (Box 16)
  - Webster, Helen S. (1), (n.d.) (Box 16)
  - Weingarten, Samuel (1), Oct. 28, 1943 (Box 16)
  - Weiss, Marie (2), Mar. 29, 1956, (n.d.) (Box 16)
  - Welch, Robert (1), Jan. 12, 1961 (Box 16)
  - Wellons, Polly (1), Mar. 8, 1941 (Box 16)
  - Wells, Rulon (2), Oct. 20, 1952 (post card), Oct. 23, 1952 (Box 16)
  - Wellysley, Will H. (1), Dec. 5, 1959 (post card) (Box 16)
  - Wessell, Nils Y. (3), Sept. 1954, Sept. 30, 1955, Mar. 1, 1959 (Box 16)
  - West, Conn Harris (1), July 30, 1951 (Box 16)
  - West, G.T. Jr. (1), July 20, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Wharton, Clifton,R. (1), Oct. l, 1935 (Box 16)
  - White, Robert H. (1), Oct. 3, 1930 (Box 16)
  - Whiteside, Amanda I. (1), July 25, 1955 (Box 16)
  - Whittemore, Helan A. (1), June 13, 1951 (Box 16)
  - Widgery, Alban G. (1), Mar. 13, 1950 (Box 16)
  - Wild, John (1), Mar. 12, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Wilder, Dolores- Allen (1), May 17, 1 57 (Box 16)
  - Wilhelmi, Hazel (2), Sept. 3, 1949 (post card), Jan. 5, 1950 (post card) (Box 16)
  - Wilkins, Roy (1), Dec. 1, 1955 (Box 16)
  - Wilkins, W.J. (5), Feb. 5, 1944, Mar. 11, 1944, r. 18, 1944, Mar. 30, 1944, May 5, 1944 (Box 16)
  - Wilkins, Walter L. (2), Dec. 23, 1949 (post card), Jan. 3, 1950 (post card) (Box 16)
  - Wilkinson, W. Scott (1), Sept. 4, 1959 (Box 16)
  - Willard, Gladys E. (1), Feb.18, 1951 (Box 16)
  - Willcox, Maude Williams (2), Apr. 23, 1961, May 14, 1961 (Box 16)
  - Williams, Edwin G. (1), July 14, 1942 (Box 16)
  - Williams, Mr.and Mrs.Edwin G. (1), Mar. 12, 1945 (Box 16)
  - Williams, H.H. (1), Apr. 25, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Williams, J.S. (1), May 12, 1952 (Box 16)
  - Williams, John J. (1), Feb. 17, 1955 (Box 16)
  - Williams, Lee (1), Oct. 23, 1951 (Box 16)
  - Williams, R.L. (1), Jan. 10, 1946 (Box 16)
  - Williams, V.S. (8), Feb. 26, 1943, Aug. 25, 1943, Oct. 17, 1944, Nov. 15, 1944, Nov. 24, 1944, Dec. 12, 1944, Apr. 2, 1945 (telegram), Apr. 3, 1945 (Box 16)
  - Willows, M. Elsie (2), Mar. 22, 1943, Jan. 25, 1950 (Box 16)
  - Wilm, E.C. (1), Oct. 22, 192 (Box 16)
  - Wilser, Frank A. (1), Jan. 8, 1935 (Box 16)
  - Winchester, Susie W. (1), June 14, 1935 (Box 16)
  - Winters, Mr. and Mrs. Martin (1), Mar. 27, 1947 (Box 16)
  - Winton, George B. (1), May 3, 1926 (Box 16)
  - Wolf, Go. (1), (n.d.) (Box 16)
  - Wolfard, Lucile L, (1), Feb. 16, 1946 (post card) (Box 16)
  - Wolfe, I. (1), Mar. 17, 19 5 (Box 16)
  - Wolfe, J.H. (1), June 26, 1944 (Box 16)
  - Wolfe, John B. (6), Dec. 14, 1949, Feb. 24, 1950, Mar. 17, 1950, Mar. 27, 1950, Feb. 6, 1952, Feb. 20, 1952 (Box 16)
  - Wolff, Albert (1), Oct. 27, 1950 (Box 16)
  - Wolff, Francis (1), Mar. 17, 1953 (Box 16)
  - Wood, Vera Miller (9), Aug. 31, 1942, Aug. 10, 1943, Aug. 3, 1944, Jan. 3, 1945, Apr. 25, 1950, July 11, 1950, July 17, 1950, Dec. 7, (n.d.) (Box 16)
  - Woodrow, W.T. (2), Nov. 6, 1945, Nov. 16, 1945 (Box 16)
  - Woodward, F.G. (1), June 12, 1945 (Box 16)
  - The Woodys (2), Feb. 14, 1952, (n.d.) (Box 16)
  - Worden, Cornelia A.J. (8), Apr. 7, 1954, Nov. 19, 1954, Feb. 16, 1955, May 20, 1955, (telegram), May 25, 1955, June 15, 1955, Jan. 13, 1956, Mar. 1 (to Miss Everett) (Box 16)
  - Worden, J. Erricson (2), Aug. 19, 1951, July 7, 1954 (telegram) (Box 16)
  - Wright, Clay (1), Jan. 12, 1946 (Box 16)
  - Wright, Lannie (1), Oct. 22, 1945 (Box 16)
  - Wright, Louis C. (1), July 8, 1943 (to John H. Melzer) (Box 16)
  - Wuichet, Margaret P. (1), Mar. 8, 1955 (to Editor of the Times) (Box 16)
  - Wuichet, West (26), Jan. 18, 1955 (to J.S. Kimmel, Sr.), Jan. 26, 1955 (to Dolores), Jan. 26, 1955 (to Jos.C. Keeley), Jan. 26, 1955 (to Geo. W. Malone), Feb. 15, 1955 (to Graham A. Barden), Feb. 26, 1955 (to George W. Malone); Feb. 26, 1955 (to Seaborn P. Collins), Feb. 26, 1955 (to John W. Bricker), Feb. 26, 1955 (to John w. Bricker), Feb. 27, 1955 (to Harold L.Putnam), Mar. 1, 1955 (to Seaborn P. Collins), Mar. 5, 1955 (to Kate); Mar. 6, 1955 (to Milton M. Lory), June 23, 1955, Aug. 18, 1955, Aug. 14, 1956 (to Frank Kirkpatrick), Nov. 26, 1956 (to w.c. Daniel), June 21, 1957 (to Aaron), June 24, 1957 (to Herman E. Talmadge), July 7, 1957 (to NormanS. Meese); July 7, 1957 (to Aaron), Jan. 20, 1960 (to Martin B. McKneally), Jan. 21, 1960 (to Aaron M. Sargent), Jan. 21, 1960, Apr. 9, 1960, (n.d.) (Box 16)
  - Yamada, Tamaki (1), Apr. 13, 1927 (Box 17)
  - Yarbrough, W.H. (3), Dec. 15, 1934, Mar. 21, 1949, Aug. 24, 1959 (Box 17)
  - Yates, Beatrice M. (1), Apr. 13, 1944 (to John H. Melzer) (Box 17)
  - Yeargan, Frank C. (1), (n.d.): (post card) (Box 17)
  - Yea, Albin (2), Nov. 1, 1933, Apr. 6, 1935 (Box 17)
  - Yellman, Y.S. (1), Nov. 28, 1944 (to C.P. Heinlein) (Box 17)
  - Yerkes, Guy E. (1), June 13, 1935 (Box 17)
  - Yoder, Fred R. (1), July 22, 1944 (to J.H. Melzer) (Box 17)
  - Youmans, John B. (3), Feb. 6, 1950, Oct. 21, 1952, Dec. 11, 1954 (Box 17)
  - Young, F.B., Jr. (1), Aug. 10, 1945 (Box 17)
  - Young, Grace P. (1), Feb. 22, 1955 (Box 17)
  - Young, Robert R. (1), Mar. 18, 1946 (Box 17)
  - Your Fellov Traveler (1), (n.d.) (Box 17)
  - Zabel, Hazel J. (5), Oct. 19, 1944, Mar. 30, 1945, Mar. 20, 1946, Apr. 5, 1946, June 10, 1946 (Box 17)
  - Zane, Silliman (1), (n.d.) (post card) (Box 17)
  - Zarbough, Harvey (1), Dec. 21, 1924 (Box 17)
  - Zibart, Carl (1), (n.d.) (Box 17)
  - Zimmerman, Waldo (1), Dec. 23 (Box 17)
  - Zuck, Warna L. (1), July 14, 1953 (Box 17)
  - C.M. (1), (n.d.) (post card) (Box 17)
  - H.T.and E.R. (1) (Box 17)
  - L.E.R. (1), (n.d.) (Box 17)
  - X.Y.Z. (1), (date illegible) (Box 17)
  - Alfw. and Elizabeth (1), Nov. 9, 1925 (post card) (Box 17)
  - Bert (1), Oct. 8, 1949 (Box 17)
  - Brover (1), July 121 1945 (post card) (Box 17)
  - Cecilia (1), Nov. 25, (poat card to Joseph Halpin) (Box 17)
  - Ed (2), Aug. 6, 1935 (post card), Aug. 11, 1935 (Box 17)
  - Ed and Sadie (4), July 29, 1935 (post card), Aug. 16, 1935 (post card), Aug. 17, 1935 (post card), Aug. 19, 1935 (poet card) (Box 17)
  - Eleanor (2), (n.d.), (n.d.) (Box 17)
  - Emma (1), (n.d.) (to Edith) (Box 17)
  - Florence (1), Oct. 11, 1935 (Box 17)
  - Florence and Freeman (2), Aug. 17, 1935, Sept. 9, 1935 (Box 17)
  - Flosaie (3), Nov. 29, 1934, Sept. 7, 1935, Dec. 6, 1935 (Box 17)
  - Franklin (2), Oct. 27, 1944, Nov. 15, 1944 (Box 17)
  - Grace and Trawell (1), Dec. 23, 1934 (Box 17)
  - Harold (2), June 13, 1935, (n.d.) (Box 17)
  - Harry and Lleanor (1) (Box 17)
  - John (1), Jan. 9, 1953 (Box 17)
  - John Paul and Marie (1), Mar. 9, 1950 (Box 17)
  - Julie (1), Apr. 8, 1935 (Box 17)
  - Leon (1), Feb. 4, 1950 (post card) (Box 17)
  - Mama and All (1), May 18, 1957 (post card) (to Mr. and Mrs.Dan Wilder) (Box 17)
  - Marguerite (1), Aug. 5, 1934 (to Belle) (Box 17)
  - Mary Alice M. (1), (n.d.) (Box 17)
  - Murphy (1), (n.d.) (Box 17)
  - Pat (1), Mar. 11, 1959 (to Arthur Omberg) (Box 17)
  - Robert (1), July 29, 1950 (Box 17)
  - Sadie (1), Aug. 11, 1935 (Box 17)
  - Weedon (1), Jan. 21, 1956 (telegram) (Box 17)
  - Illegible (18) (Box 17)
- Research Notes, Approxilllately 2000 pages of holograph and typescript notes on a variety of subjects, including philosophy, psychology, communism, internationalism, dashunds, and goats. (Box 17, Box 18, Box 19)
- Notebooks and Scrapbooks, Material consists of 4 holograph and typescript notebooks, and 2 scrapbooks which belonged to Sanborn. (Box 19)
- Writings by Sanborn, Material includes 101 published and unpublished works by Sanborn. There are essays, leaflets, reprints, articles, book reviews, rough drafts and aanuscripts, alphabetically arranged by title. Academic Libertinism; Aesthetics and Civilization; Aesthetics and Metaphysics; The American Way; Are There Any Individuals?; The Assassination of the Republic; An Attempt to Develop A Phylogenetic Habit; Attempts to Develop a Phylogenetic Habit; The Basis of Consolidation; The Biology of the Race Problem; A Review; Communisn and the Metro-Plan; Communism and the Problem of Academic Freedom; Communism, Internationalism and Freedom; A Critical Review of Publications in "The Politicaan" and "American Opinion"; "The Curse of The Foundations"; Dachshund Notes; The Dachshund or Teckel; Dachshunds; Dachshunds at Albany; The Danger from Rabies; Vaccination; Davenport's Contribution to the Use of Graphical. Methods in Logic; De Mortuis nil nisi bonum; Deocracy, Science, and Philosophy; The Democratic Control of Education; Desegregation and Ethics; Dingler's Last Discovery; Dingler's Methodical. Philosophy; The Dogaa of Non-Transference; The Doom and Nemesis of Our Internationalism; Dovn-East Spirituals and Others by George Pullen Jackson, revieved by Sanborn; Dr. Sanborn's Platform; Education that Universalizes; Essays on Faith and Moral.s, Pgrgmatism, Radical Empiricism and A Pluralistic Universe, 3 revievs by Sanborn; The Ethics of Hugo Dingler; An Examination of Williaa Stern's Philosophy; Fichte's Clssed Commercial State; The Fouteenth Amendment; Freedom Forgotten and Remembered by Helmut Kuhn, reviewed by Sanborn; The Function of Clothing and of Bodily Adornaent; The Function of Language Study in Liberal Education; The Function of Philosophy in Liberal Education; German Philosophy and Politics by John Devey, revieved by Sanborn; The Great Conspiracy to Destroy the United States; Die Grundlagen einer experimentelle Bildungspsychologie by Werner Straub, revieved by Sanborn; The Hidden Hand; Horace Williams Gadfly of Chapel Hill by Robert Watson, reviewed by Sanborn; Hugo Dingler - What is Conventialism?; The Inheritance of Song In Birds; The International Conspiracy; Internationalism and Zionism; Internationalism - By Way of U.S. Aid to Education; Is the Reaction of the South Emotional?; Dant's Contributions to Science; Lines for a "Dying Republic"; Man and His Works by Edward Lee Thron-Dike, reviewed by Sanborn; The Meaning fo Internationalism; The Meaning of Philosophy of the Southern Association for Philosophy and Psychology; The Meeting Point of Philosophy and Psychology; Methodology and Aesthetics; Methodology and the Monkey States; Methodology and the Problem of Language; Methodology and The Problem of Musical Expression; Methodology and the Problem of the Southern Society for Philosophy and Psychology; The Monkey States; Music; A New Dachshund Star; Observations of Apparently Unlearned Behavior; On War by Karl Von Clausewitz, reviewed by Sanborn; Philosophical Tranactions 1773; Philosophia Perennis Edited by Fritz-Joachim Von Rintelen, reviewed by Sanborn; La Philosophie de l'art Classique by Draguicha Lapcevic, Reviewed by Sanborn; Philosophies and Psychologies; The Philosophy of G.E. Moore; The Philosophy of Wilhelm Wundt; Post Election Relections; The Principles of Power by Giuglielmo Ferrere, Reviewed by Sanborn; The Problem of Language; The Problem of Psychic Reality; Problems of Constitutionality; Psychology and Epistemology; Rabies by Leslie T. Webster, Reviewed by Sanborn; The Rabies Manace; The Rabies Racket; Religion, Psychology And Philosophy; A Review of Aristotelian Aesthetics; Review of "Rabies"; Selected Paintings by Rembrandt, Reviewed by Sanborn; A Side-Light On The Katharsis; The Spirit of Martin Luther; The Spirit of Tragic Drama; Summa Jus, Summa Injuria; Teckel Note Tendencies in American Dachshund Breeding; Thucydides On History As Philosophy; Tragedy as a Work of Art; What the United Nations Really Is; Which War are we At or About to be At?; 6 untitled writings. (Box 20, Box 21, Box 22)
- Business Papers, Approximately 1,000 items, including bank atateaents, bank deposit tickets, bills and receipts, income tax papers, royalty statements, stock certificates and automobile insurance papers, chronologically arranged by year, from 1908-1963. (Box 22, Box 23, Box 24)
- Newspaper and Magazine Clippings of Articles by Sanborn, Material includes approximately 50 clippings, dealing with a variety of subjects, from fluoridation to dachshunds to politics. (Box 24)
- Newspaper and Magazine Clippings About Sanborn, Material consists of approximately 25 clippings about Herbert Charles Sanborn. (Box 25)
- Reprints and Offprints, Thirty-four, alphabetically arranged by title: A Call to Action In American Education; Can Roman Catholics Be Loyal to Both America and the Vatican?; Carlos Everett Conant; Change In Size Of The After-Image Induced In Total Darkness; Creative Thought In Artists; The Designation Of Combination Tones; The Emergence of Racial Genetics; Ends Versus Goals in Foreign-Language Study; Eurhythmic; Functional Logic; If the U.S. Becomes 51% Catholic!; Man the Measure; Migratory Behavior In Song Sparrows; Morea and the Moon; Nesting Suceess During Three Seasons In A Song Sparrow Population; A Note on Symbolic Inversion; Proceedings of the Forty-Third Annual Meeting Of The Southern Society For Philosophy and Psychology; Proceedings of The Forty-Fifth Annual Meeting Of The Southern Society For Philosophy And Psychology; Proceedings of the Forty-Sixth Annual Meeting Of The Southern Society For Philosophy and Psychology; The Psychological Laboratory of The University of Texas; The Psychology of Music; Racial Attitudes Among White And Negro Children In A Deep-South Standard Metropolitan Area; The Racial History Of Scandinavia; Relations Between The Sexes In Song Sparrows; Remarks About The Phenomenological Program; The Role Of Graphical Methods In The History Of Logic; The Social Aspects Of Population Dynamics; Society, Ideas and Cultural Achievement; Some Refeections on Freedom; The Study Of Wild Animals Under Controlled Conditions; The Theodosian Code and Novels and the Sirmondian Constitutions; The Theory Of Territorialism And Its Development; Who Is To Bear Primary Responsibility For The Psychological Disorders?; Yogurt. (Box 25)
- Writings by Others, Material consists of 44 works by others, including poems, essays, and research paper Alphabetically arranged by title, writings are typescript, holograph, and carbon copies. Acetonemia, A Vitamin Deficiency; Aesthetics And The Biology Of The Fleeting Moment; The Atlantic City Dog how; Aus dem Amerikanischen Buchereiwesen; Ballade en toc a la Lune attique; The Bankrupt; Berkeleyan Aspects of Wordsworth's Thought; Bishop Oxnam Flunks His Test; Prepared "Proof" of Anti-Communism not Convincing; The Breathless Void; Carolina-Virginia Dog Show Circuit April 14-27, 1942; Contr Dingler Pro Dingler; Educational Freedom - Or - Educational Control?; General Terms In Geography; The Goats in Russia; Harry Truman's President's Commission On Higher Education - 1947; Hermitage; How To Philosophize; Intuoduction To The Study Of The Electrophysiology Of The African Negro Ist die Entwicklung der Lebewesen eine Idee oder eine Tatsache?; Long Live The Irish; The Man In The Gap; May Jones Take the Air; The Mortain Counterattack; My Day; Nationalism and World Citizenship, Striking A Sane Balance; The Nervous Man; One Fundamental; The Philosopher's Scales; A Plea For Psychologists' Interest In Psychical Research; Plowman's Folly Refute The Principle of Epistemological Co-ordination in N.O.Losski's Theory of Knowledge; Psycho-Politics and Mental Health Propaganda; Segregation Predates History; Shall We Continue Latin And Greek In Our Schools?; Should We Undertake Systems Today?; Signs, Symbols, And Vagueness In Language; Suamary of a ConTersation with Chancellor Carmichael with Professor Donald Davidson, February 4, 1942; Summary of the Kritik of Pure Reason; There Are No Values or Value-Noun of Verb. Or On Pulling A Cat'a Tail; To The Intellectual Fighters of Paris and Vienna; "What Others Think"; William Stern's Theory Of Personalism and Lasski's Theory Of Concrete Ideal-Realism; Winter; A Workshop For Philosophers of The American Academy of Philosophy. (Box 25, Box 26)
- Newspapers, Newspaper Clipping, There are approximately 300 newspaper clippings, and 8 newspapers. Newspapers are alphabetically arranged by title: Common Sense; Free Enterprise; Free Men Speak; Industrial Weekly; The Manchester Guardian Weekly; Militant Truth; The National Flouridation News; West Nashville News. (Box 27)
- Magazines, Magazine Clippings, Material consists of approximately 100 magazine clippings and 74 magazines, alphabetically arranged by title: Alpine Pastures; The American Dachshund; American Dairy Goat News; American Fencing; The American Nationalist; Another Language; Behavior Mono-graphs; Beilage der Munchner Neuesten Nachrichten; Boston University Bulletin; Bulletin of The Dairy Research Bureau; Bulletin of Vanderbilt Univeristy; Challenge To Socialism; The Christian Century; Congressional Record; Dachs and Dashes; Der Dachshund; The Dashahund Club of America; The Dachshund Digest; Dachshund Diggings: The Defenders' News and Views; Economic Liberty; Ethical Culture Today; Freedom Facts; Gaines Dog Research Progress; The Greater Nebraskan; Headlines And What's Behind Them; Human Events; Humanities in the South; The Journal of Philosophy; Kansas Dairy Goat Society Gazette; The Kennel News Bulletin; The Key Reporter; The Last Word in Kennel Science; The Liberty Bell; The Manion Forum; Modern Dogs; Monatshefte fur deutshce Sprache und Padagogik; Monographs Of The Society For Research In Child Development; National Defender; National Miniature Dachshund Club News; National Renaissance Bulletin; Nationalist Party Bulletin; Natural Food And Farming; The News; News and Views; Newsweek; Northern World; Orange Peelings; Perceptual And Motor Skills; The Personalist; The Phi Betta Kappa Key; The Philosophical Review; Psychological Abstracts; Reconstructionist; The Reformation Review; The Revere; Right; School And Society; Scentific Monthly; South The News Magazine of Dixie; South Atlantic Bulletin; The Southern Philosophies; The Southern Society for Philosophy And Paychology; Southern States Industrial Council Bulletin; The Standard; Task Force; The Thunder bolt; Time The Weekly News Magazine; Tufts Alumni Review; U.S.A. An American Bulletin of Fact and Opinion; Williams Intelligence summary; Women's Voice. (Box 27, Box 28, Box 29)
- Pedigree Papers, Material includes approximately 250 pedigree papers for dogs and goats. Also included are several applications for litter registtation and for transfer of ownership. certificates of health; and certificates of stud service. (Box 29)
- Miscellaneous Writings, Material consists of approximately 500 typescript pages. There are committee reports; annual reports; speeches and statements; constitutions and by-laws of various organizations; biographical sketches; minutes of meetings; and transcripts of court proceedings. (Box 30)
- Photographs, Appromimately 200 photographs of dogs, goats, people, and buildings. (Box 30, Box 31)
- Programs, There are 51 programs of philosophical meetings, musical and theatrical performances, religious services, and dog shows, chronologically arranged from 1921 to 1960. (Box 31)
- Advertisements, Material includes approzimately 300 advertisements for books, plants, foods, animal products, and tourist attractions. (Box 31, Box 32)
- Pamphlets, Flyers, There are approximately 600 pamphlets and flyers dealing with a wide variety of subjects, from segregation to communism to dachshunds. (Box 32, Box 33, Box 34)
- Phonograph Records, There are 62 records, 61 of which contain bird songs. There is also a recording of a speech by Chancellor J.H. Kirkland. (Box 34, Box 35, Box 36)